敵の意志をくじく！ 戦う意志を
By using...
立ち上がる意志を あらがう意志を
words?
悟らせてやろう
King...
お前の努力と自信 いかに無意味なものかをな！
Would you like to know your name?
勘で俺が爆破しないと 判断したか？ いや　あの顔は違う！
Centipede x And x Memory
自分の爆発で やけどをしないんだろう)) ((簡単よ　爆発の攻撃力より 大きいオーラで
As the King and Netero prepared
for their final battle...
((うん　２回目はビスケのオーラが 少なくなった)) ) ((その違いを感じ取れれば 奴との戦いが少しだけ楽よ))
Beneath the palace, Ikalgo was still sobbing, having failed to finish off
the unconscious Brovada.
腕や足なら表皮は焼け 神経や筋肉に重大な障害が残る。
Fire! This is the best option!
指なら跡形もなく消し飛ぶだろう。
There's no one else to help me!
お前が俺の「凝」での攻撃を　全て 「凝」でガードするのは不可能。
I h-have to... kill him!
できれば　これ以上　やりたくない 戦ってみて　よく分かった。
This is no time to be crying...
お前には才能があり　未来があり 次のチャンスもある。
I have to find Palm! Huh?
意地だけで　その全てを捨てるのは あまりに無意味だと思わないか？
The door to the warehouse area is open. So is the door leading to the garage!
さっさと諦めろ このクソガキが！
Why? Don't move!
((もしも奴が　両手を爆発に 使うようなそぶりを見せたら もう赤信号よ))
If you move, I'll attack.
((何をおいても 作戦実行にのみ集中すること))
Welfin...
ごめん　ビスケ　キルア ここから先は　俺のわがまま
I have a lot of things to ask you.
試さないと気が済まないんだ
If you seem to be trying anything funny, I'll kill you!
だって 思いついちゃったから！
What he wants to ask me
もし　本当に そう思っているなら お前が降りろ！　ゲンスルー！
is obvious! The number of my allies, their roles, and their abilities.
残念だ。
And he intends to use any means
necessary to get the answers.
教えてやろう。 世の中には死ぬより つらいことなど
People could die if I leak information.
いくらでもあるとな！ 両腕を同時に爆破する。
If he's a Manipulator, he can obtain the information against my will.
無事に残しておきたいほうを 「凝」で守れ。
Huh?
その次に残ったほうの腕と左足を 同時に爆破する。
D-Don't move! I really will kill you! Go ahead... Kill me.
残したいほうを「凝」で守れ それを延々と続ける。 手足がなくなるまでな。
That's what I want! Stop! If the alternative is betraying my buddies, I'll take you with me!
やれるもんならやってみろ！ では。
Ouch! Bastard! Now you've done it!
くらえ！
Missile Man!
くっ…　な…　何が起きた？
I'm... not dead... I didn't sustain any damage. What was that attack?
血？　ダメージ？ 俺が攻撃されたのか？
Damn, that hurts... You little punk... Damn...
最初は　グ！ ヤバい！　動け！ よけるんだ！
That bastard... How did a wimp like
that figure out my weakness?
ジャン！　ケン！
Missile Man requires questions and answers to work.
グ!!
If an enemy attacks before I can ask
a question, it's null and void!
く…　うっ…。
The wound isn't deep... I'll take my time beating him to a pulp.
何だ？　今のは　何が起きた？
Huh?
くっ！　こいつ… 左右の手でダメージが違う！
He planted something inside me?
おそらく左手は完全に捨てて
Those were created by my Nen.
右手を 攻防力３０程度のオーラで覆い
They're black centipedes.
残りの攻防力７０を 足に集中させて… 俺を攻撃した！
They grow by feeding on your resistance.
それを両手同時に消費すれば 他の箇所のオーラは 極度に少なくなる そこを突かれた！ しかし… 考えついても普通やるか？ ひと泡　吹かせてやったぞ！
If you disobey my orders or try to hurt me, you'll suffer excruciating pain, then they'll tear your body apart and you'll die!
けど…　動くぞ！
Wh-What are you doing, fool? Weren't you listening to me?
もう…　いいや。 「もういい」？　諦めたか？
If you try to do that...
左手は吹き飛ばされて 右手も重傷 俺への反撃も決まり 一矢報いた
That's fine with me.
十分　満足したはず
If my life is all it takes, I'll give it!
ここからが本番だ 行くぞ　ゲンスルー！
S-Stop!
イカれてやがる！
No, wait...
ブック！ カード？　特に 警戒するものは　なかったはず
Now, it'll take no time for the black centipedes
to grow large enough to kill him instantly!
カードが変身… 「聖騎士の首飾り」か！ 一体　何をする気だ？
Don't worry. I'm not interested in killing you...
諦めるなら　今のうちだぞ。 これを使うと　最悪の場合 お前は　死ぬかもしれない。
I just need to make sure that you can't leave. I still...
だが　待てよ… これは　チャンスだ
have plenty of bullets.
ブック。
Bastard! Don't mess with me!
根負けだ　どうやっても
I'll kill you!
お前に参ったと 言わせるのは　無理なようだ。
You're dead! I'll kill you!
チッ！　２撃目は 「凝」でガードされたか
It's so easy.
もう　これで　こいつは 「ブック」も「ゲイン」も唱えられない！ ゲンスルー お前は　一番 やっちゃいけないことをした
When I'm prepared to offer my own life, it's so easy to pull the trigger.
その触れた箇所に　爆弾を 仕掛けることができる能力だ。
I g-get it... I get it, already.
爆弾を解除するためには 俺の体に触れて
I won't go anywhere!
「ボマー捕まえた」と 言わねばならない。
I surrender. Please... Don't fire!
お前の「念」で 防ぎ切れるレベルじゃないぞ。
The pain is going away.
これで　発動条件は整った。
The creatures inside me are suffering?
お前に触れて「ボマー」と言えば 自動的に爆弾は　スタートする。
I lose, damn it... I can't move anymore.
せいぜい逃げてみろ。 そんな余力があればな。 条件が整ったのは
Is it because Welfin admitted defeat?
最初は　グ…。 うっ！
Man, I knew it...
これだ　さっきのだ 踏み込めば　やられる！
I had a feeling this would happen eventually.
近寄らせない気か!?
But still...
ジャン！　ケン！
I didn't think I was this weak!
グ!!
I didn't think it'd be so scary
to face someone who fights
あっ！　落とし穴!! しかし　奴も落ちてるぞ!?
What? The pain has stopped, but can
you get rid of these bugs?
高い…　とても登れん！
Hurry up.
だが　それは　奴も同じはず この状況じゃ 追い詰められたのは
Give me a minute!
逆に奴のほうじゃないか！
I don't have a way to deactivate Missile Man.
いない!?
But if I tell the truth, I'm in real trouble...
ゲンスルー…。 なっ…！
Damn, how do I get out of this?
カードは　バインダーから出して １分経つと
I need to buy time...
アイテムに戻る！
Until I can come up with a good idea.
岩!?
The pain is making me... feel faint...
うっ！
Wait! Okay!
ジャン！　ケン！
I was lying! I won't do it again!
ま…　待て！　参った!!
Then get rid of these.
参った!!
Yeah, uh...
グ!!
So, the thing is...
ふぅ…。
I can't remove them!
オス!!
Not once they've been activated!
気づいたか？
I'm not trying to trick you!
早速だけど　バインダー出して。
The insects are in pain again.
あんた達が仲間を裏切って 手にしたカード
Maybe because Welfin is telling the truth?
全部　返してもらうわさ。
Can you really blame me?
条件がある。 「大天使」で バラを治してやってくれ
I only use this attack when I want to kill someone. I never cared what happened after that.
「クローン」は　ある。
I never gave any thought to
what happened to my enemy.
安心しろよ　初めっから そのつもりだから。 こっちは　あらかじめ ６人分の「クローン」を
Nen abilities are really something.
用意してたわさ。
My abilities reflect my own personality.
ブック。
My personality? His true intentions?
わらわに　何を望む？
I once knew someone just like him.
こいつの両手と喉を元通りに 治してもらいたいんだけど。
Do you have any memories from
when you were human?
あっ　つうか できれば悪いとこ全部。
Wh-Why are you asking about that?
お安いご用。
I can't remember...
では　その者の体 治してしんぜよう。 フ。
You're lying.
あ…。 あっ！
If you don't tell me the truth, I'll shoot you.
はい　もう１枚　予備の「大天使」。
When I woke up, my first thought was...
次は　キルアね。 ゲンスルー　あんたのバインダー 使わせてもらうわよ。
I can still remember it.
「大天使の息吹」は カード化限度枚数がＭＡＸです。 「クローン」は　破壊されます。
I'm sure those monster bugs killed me in NGL.
「大天使の息吹」の 引換券を増やしたんだ。 今頃は　あっちの引換券が２枚 「大天使」になってるよ。
I was fed to the Queen,
and reborn as something new...
他のプレーヤーがあなたに対し 「コンタクト」を使用しました。 よう！　ゴレイヌだ。 どうやら　勝ったようだな。
But I still... I still remember the one thing
I most wanted to forget.
納得いかねえ。 こんな人殺しの連中に 「大天使」を使うのなら トレードは断る。
The sight of my father strangling me, and the woman watching behind him.
俺も　殺し屋だぜ。 え？ こいつら以上に　人を殺してる。
At first, I only had flashbacks of it.
このゲームには　みんな 大なり小なり　命を懸けて来てる。
Over time, I remembered the
entire sequence of events.
俺が殺して来たのは
I was saved by...
そんな覚悟から 程遠い所にいた人ばかり。 俺のほうが　よっぽど たち悪いだろ。
my little brother, who was unrelated by blood.
いや お前と　こいつらとは違う。
I remember now!
俺は　お前を気に入っているが こいつらのことは大嫌いだ！ それ　理屈になってねえよ！
He looked just like Gyro!
お前らだって　同じだろ！
You know. The king!
私達は　彼らを 見殺しにしていいとは考えません。
We used to brag about whose
life was more miserable.
戦う時は　お互い命懸けだし 相手を殺すくらいの覚悟で 臨みます。
He was the only one I could
turn to when I needed
でも　勝負がついたら その先は　話が違います。
to laugh away my tears...
俺だって　ゲンスルーが 大勢のプレーヤーを殺したこと
We were both empty.
許してないよ。 でも　戦う前に３人で決めたんだ。
So we had nothing to hide.
「クローン」は ６枚　用意しておこうって。 その時の会話の流れは よく覚えてないけど。
I wonder what he's doing now...
勝負がついて 「大天使の息吹」が手に入ったら 誰がケガしても治そうって。
I want to see him one more time...
事情が変わって 「クローン」が使えなくなった。 「大天使」は　あと１枚しかない。
Yes, I just want to see Gyro.
あと１枚って お前ら　それ　オリジナルだろ！ 俺は平気だ。
I'm tired of dealing with Ants and humans, with money and nations...
あ…。
The bugs are gone.
んじゃ　このまま「アカンパニー」で マサドラ行くか！
You still have something to do.
おい　待てよ！ 分かった　お前らにやるよ！ 「大天使の息吹」。
Why did you open the doors?
えっ？ えっ　いいの？　ホントに？ ああ　つうか ここに来て話を聞く前は
Oh, I was letting those weaklings
reach the treasure in the back.
「大天使」だけじゃなく 俺達のカード　全部な。 えっ！
They can't put up much of a fight.
これは　ツェズゲラ含め 俺達５人　全員の合意だ。
I was watching you and Bro on the monitor.
俺達は　もうゲームを降りたんだ。
And I told them to pass while
you were on the way back.
ああ　ツェズゲラ達に 違約金を払う形でな。 俺も４０億で手を打ったよ。
A coward!
４０億!? ちょっと！ それ　少し　よこしなさいよ！
It was that simple.
何　言ってんだよ！ ４人で　１０億ずつ 分けるに決まってんだろ。 え！ 当然だろう。 これは　俺１人の力じゃ　ない。
Once I saw that you couldn't finish Bro, I couldn't have been more wrong.
あんたって奴は…。
Go on.
なんて　いい奴なんだわさ！
I'm too tired to move...
とにかく　このカードは 全て　お前達にやる。 条件は　たった一つ。
I have one last question. Did you see a woman in the palace?
必ず　お前らが 最初にクリアすること。
A woman?
うん！ 問題なし。 これで 指定ポケットカードは９９枚。
Not sure if it's the one you're talking about, but the Royal Guard captured a human,
and put her in a cocoon.
残るは ナンバー０　のみってわけだ。
Where is she?
残り１枚…。 あぁ。
Take the elevator up, then turn left.
９７　９８…。
It's the room at the end of the hall. They called it #1.
そして　これが
Thank you!
プレーヤーの方々に お知らせです。 たった今　あるプレーヤーが
Telling the truth
９９種の指定ポケットカードを そろえました。
feels really good...
それを記念いたしまして 今から１０分後に 『グリードアイランド』内にいる プレーヤー全員参加の クイズ大会を開始いたします。
Welfin had spent his life unable
to trust himself or others.
指定ポケットカードに関する 問題です。
Telling Ikalgo the location of
the one he searched for
正解率の最も高かった プレーヤーに賞品としまして
was the first time he'd opened
up and spoken honestly.